Morris, James O., Office Files /4073
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James O. Morris Office Files
1890-1985
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Morris, James O.
/4073
35 cubic feet
35 linear ft.
Records (documents).
7980445
Biographical / Historical
James O. Morris (February 8, 1923 June 30, 1985) was professor of industrial and labor relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of Hiram College and the University of Michigan, Morris joined the faculty of Cornell University in 1955. In the 1950s and early 1960s, he spent time in Chile as a Fulbright scholar and the ILR School's representative at the University of Chile in Santiago. After his time in Chile, Morris returned to Ithaca and taught in Cornell's Department of Collective Bargaining, Labor Law, and Labor History.
Morris was the author of Conflict within the AFL: A Study of Craft versus Industrial Unionism, 1900-1938 (Ithaca: Cornell, 1958), Elites, Intellectuals and Consensus: A Study of the Social Question and the Industrial Relations Systems in Chile (Ithaca: Cornell, 1966), Bibliography of Industrial Relations in the Railroad Industry (Ithaca: Cornell, 1975), and with Roberto Oyaneder, Afiliacion y finanzas sindicales en Chile, 1932-1959 (Santiago: University of Chile Press, 1966).
Morris served on the editorial board of Labor History and Industrial and Labor Relations Review, and was a founding member of the New York State Labor History Association, a group for which he also served terms as vice president and president.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor James Morris: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18150
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3018: James O. Morris Papers /4055: James O. Morris Office Files /4056: James O. Morris Papers
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 26, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 04, 2019
Morris, James O.
7980445
- Cornell Campus Disturbances, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes news clippings
- Cornell Campus Disturbances continued, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Rockefeller Position Reports, 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- David Brody's Comments and Trends in Labor History, 1955-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Search Committee - Historian 1972, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Irving Ives Biography, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Robert McKersie - Dean of the ILR School, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- James Morris Materials on Cornell Campus Disturbances, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- E.P. Thompson, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Excepts from Thompson's book The Making of the English Working Class
- Cletus Daniel, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Book review of Daniel's The CLU and the Wagner Act
- Editorial Board - Labor History, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Labor History Editorial Board 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- James Morris - Salary, 1959-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Labor History Board Meeting, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ken Gilroy, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Library Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Professor Morris - WATS Code Number, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Bibliography, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Records of Microfilmed Papers Copied (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Wisconsin, 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes a street map of the vicinity around the Madison Inn
- AFL Executive Council 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- AFL Executive Council 1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Research Trips, Maps, Correspondence, etc., 1970-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Includes a Travel Map of Minneapolis, St. Paul, and the surrounding area and a street map of Philadelphia
- 1908 Elections (Box 2, Folder 7)
- AFL - 1902 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- AFL - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- AFL - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- AFL - 1906 (January 3-July 9) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- AFL - 1906 (July 9-September 20) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- AFL - 1906 (September 20-December 29) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- AFL - 1907 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- AFL - 1908 (January 13-June 13) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- AFL - 1908 (June 17-August 22) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- AFL - 1908 (August 24-September 22) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- AFL - 1908 (September 22-Sepember 28) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- AFL - 1908 (September 29-October 22) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- AFL - 1908-1909 (October 23-January 5) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- AFL - 1909 (January 9-December 22) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- AFL - 1909-1910 (December 23-May 24) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- AFL - 1910 (May 24-September 28) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- AFL - 1910 (September 28-December 20) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- AFL - 1910-1911 (December 27-March 21) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- AFL - 1911 (March 25-October 30) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- AFL - 1911-1912 (December 6-April 9) (Box 2, Folder 27)
- AFL - 1912 (May 6-Sepember 21) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- AFL - 1912-1913 (September 18-June 8) (Box 2, Folder 29)
- AFL - 1913 (January 16-April 24) (Box 2, Folder 30)
- AFL - 1913 (April 30-December 30) (Box 2, Folder 31)
- AFL - 1914 (January 13-August 5) (Box 2, Folder 32)
- AFL - 1914 (August 12-October 9) (Box 2, Folder 33)
- AFL - 1914-1915 (October 12-July 7) (Box 2, Folder 34)
- AFL - 1915 (June-October) (Box 2, Folder 35)
- AFL - 1915-1916 (November 21-February 18) (Box 2, Folder 36)
- AFL - 1916 (March 1-May 11) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- AFL - 1916 (May 15-August 23) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- AFL - 1916 (August 24-September 16 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- AFL - 1916 (September 19-October 12) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- AFL - 1916 (October 14-November 9) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- AFL - 1916-1917 (November 6-January 31) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- AFL - 1917 (February 1-April 19) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- AFL - 1917 (May 7-August 25) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- AFL - 1917-1918 (August 21-February 7) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- AFL - 1918 (February 27-April 12) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- AFL - 1918 (April 13-July 30 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- AFL - 1918-1919 (July-October) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- AALL and Gompers 1908-1915 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- AFL - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1935 - Legislation - Executive Council on Wagner Bill (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Election of 1900 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Election of 1904 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Analysis of Vote in 1912 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Progressives in the Republican Party 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 1896 Election (Box 3, Folder 20)
- People's Party 1890-1894 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Democratic Party and Labor in the Latter 1800s (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Bull Fighting, Latin American, and Ernest Hemingway, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Includes Spanish language material, includes computer punch cards
- Unclassified Book Passages (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Death, 1951-1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- J. Hampton Moore Papers, 1908-1912 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- W. B. Wilson (Philadelphia Trip), 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1906, 1903-1906 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1908, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1909 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1910 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1911 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1912 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1914 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1915 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1916 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- W. B. Wilson Papers 1918 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Ludlow Massacre 1914 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Ludlow Massacre 1914 continued (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Ludlow Massacre 1915 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Politics in the 1890s - Paul Glad (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Rogin and Shouer - Political Change in California (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Excerpts from the Journal Labor, 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Politics - Mitchell 1, 1900-1908 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Politics - Mitchell 2, 1902-1907 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Politics - Mitchell 3, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Politics - Mitchell 4, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Politics - Mitchell 6, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Politics - Mitchell 6, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Politics - Mitchell 7, 1908-1909 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Politics - Mitchell 8, 1900-1908 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Politics - Mitchell 9, 1906-1908 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 1902 Anthracite Strike and Elihu Root (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Thomas J. Morgan, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- John J. Esch, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Raymond Robins, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- James A. Tawney, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- John Mandt Nelson, 1910, 1910-1939 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- John J. Esch, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Raymond Robins, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Raymond Robins, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Politics - Mitchell 10, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Politics - Mitchell 11, 1910-1912 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Politics - Mitchell 12, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Martin Mulhall - Term Paper by Karen Eells, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  May 6, 1977
- Mulhall - House Lobby Hearings 1, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Mulhall - House Lobby Hearings 2, 1907-1912 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Mulhall - House Lobby Hearings 3, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Mulhall - House Lobby Hearings 4, 1906-1912 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Mulhall - House Lobby Hearings 5, 1908-1913 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Immigrants - Parties and Voting Behaviors (Box 4, Folder 28)
  From Hofstadter's The Age of Reform
- Littlefield Campaign, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Parties before 1896 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Populists - General (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Progressive Movement - General (Box 4, Folder 32)
- 1896 Election (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Bryan - General Information (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Congress (Box 4, Folder 35)
  From the Era of Theodore Roosevelt
- Theodore Roosevelt - General, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- TR and 1902 Coal Strike (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Sherman Act (Box 4, Folder 38)
- 1906 Election (Box 4, Folder 39)
- 1908 Election (Box 4, Folder 40)
- William Howard Taft - General (Box 4, Folder 41)
- 1910 Election (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Opponents of House Speaker Cannon (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Oscar Straus and 1908 Campaign (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Oscar Straus and TR Administration (Box 4, Folder 45)
  From Cohen's A Dual Heritage
- Defeat for Cannon 1910 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  From George Norris's Fighting Liberal
- Taft and US Steel 1911 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  The Autobiography of John Hays Hammond
- William B. Wilson 1910-1912 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  From Norris's Fighting Liberal
- TR in Early 1912 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Progressive Party and 1912 Campaign (Box 4, Folder 50)
  From Cohen's Dual Heritage
- AFL - Background to B of G (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Woodrow Wilson, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Woodrow Wilson Correspondence, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Woodrow Wilson telegrams, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- 1890s-1900s Republican and Democratic Parties Constituencies (Box 4, Folder 55)
  From Malcolm Moose's The Republicans
- 1892 Election (Box 4, Folder 56)
  From Moose's The Republicans
- Populist Party, 1892 and later (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Pullman and Cleveland (Box 4, Folder 58)
- 1896 Election (Mark Hanna) (Box 4, Folder 59)
- 1936 Election (Box 4, Folder 60)
- 1940 Election (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Voting Behavior - Vote Buying (Box 4, Folder 62)
  From Arthur Link's first volume of his biography of Woodrow Wilson
- Ohio, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Illinois, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Illinois, May 5-June 29, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Illinois, June 30-July 22, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Illinois, July 24-August 9, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Illinois, August 10-28, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Illinois, August 28-September 6, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Illinois, September 7-20, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Illinois, September 22-October 6, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Illinois, October 7-December 29, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Illinois, December 29, 1925-February 9, 1926, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Illinois, February 11-March 19, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Illinois, March 20-April 18, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Illinois, April 18-August 30, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Illinois, August 31-November 24, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Illinois, November 29, 1926-March 21, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Illinois, 1928-1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Henrik Shipstead - 1930s, 1928-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Henry Cabot Lodge (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Theodore Roosevelt (Box 5, Folder 4)
  From John A. Garraty's biography of Henry Cabot Lodge
- TR Papers #1, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- TR Papers #2, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- TR Papers #3, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- TR Papers #4, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- TR Papers, April 17-June 18, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- TR Papers, June 22-September 14, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- TR Papers, September 15-October19, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- TR Papers, October 21-November 25, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- TR Papers, June 6-Ocotber 14, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- TR Papers, October 16-November 9, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- TR 1912 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Wilson Administration - General (Box 5, Folder 16)
  From Link's biography of Wilson
- Wilson, Labor and 1912 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  From Lin k's biography of Wilson
- Champ Clark (Box 5, Folder 18)
  From Link's Wilson and the Progressive Era
- William B. Wilson (Box 5, Folder 19)
- 1912 - General (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Wilson's Labor Views before 1912 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- 1912 - Bull Moose Movement (Box 5, Folder 22)
- 1912 Campaign and TR (Box 5, Folder 23)
  From John A. Gable's The Bull Moose Years
- 1914 Election and TR (Box 5, Folder 24)
  From Gable's The Bull Moose Years
- New York State Federation of Labor, 1864-1923 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- United Mine Workers - Executive Board Minutes, 1931-1947 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- United Mine Workers - Executive Board Minutes continued, 1950-1959 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- United Mine Workers - Executive Board Minutes Part 3, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- United Mine Workers - Executive Board Minutes Part 4, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- United Mine Workers - FDR, 1933-1939 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- United Mine Workers - 1928 Election, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Includes photocopies of news clippings
- Labor's Non-Partisan League (LNPL) - 1936, General Maters (Box 5, Folder 32)
- LNPL - 1936, State Leagues (Box 5, Folder 33)
- LNPL - 1936, Financial Matters (Box 5, Folder 34)
- LNPL - 1937, Resignation of George Berry (Box 5, Folder 35)
- LNPL - 1937, Financial Matters (Box 5, Folder 36)
- LNPL - 1937, State Leagues (Box 5, Folder 37)
- LNPL - 1937, General Matters (Box 5, Folder 38)
- LNPL - 1938, General Matters (Box 5, Folder 39)
- LNPL - 1938, Financial Matters (Box 5, Folder 40)
- LNPL - 1938, State Leagues (Box 5, Folder 41)
- LNPL - 1939, General Matters (Box 5, Folder 42)
- LNPL - 1939, Financial Matters (Box 5, Folder 43)
- LNPL - 1939, State Leagues (Box 5, Folder 44)
- LNPL - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- United Mine Workers - LNPL, 1940-1972 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Taft - April 28-June 9, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Taft - May 4-July 20, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Taft - June 12-18, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Taft - June 19-30, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Taft - July 1-13, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Taft - July 14-20, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Taft - July 21-30, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Taft - August 3-11, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Taft - August 12-18, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Taft - August 19-31, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Taft - September 2-9, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Taft - September 10-13, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Taft - September 14-16, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Taft - September 18-30, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Taft - October 1-9, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Taft - October 10-14, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Taft - October 15-18, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Taft - October 19-22, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Taft - October 22-26, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Taft - October 27-29, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Taft - October 30-November 3, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Taft - November 4-10, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Taft - July 29-August 22, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Taft - August 25-November 6, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Taft - November 7-December 2, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Taft - Mitchell and 1908, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Taft and B.B. Ray - April 20-August 22, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Taft and B.B. Ray - August 23-September 14, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Taft and B.B. Ray - September 14-October 5, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Taft and B.B. Ray - October 8-December 4, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Taft and B.B. Ray - May 9, 1910-March 5, 1912, 1910-1912 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Taft - February 24-September 20, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Taft - September 21-November 10, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Taft - December 15, 1911-November 10, 1912, 1911-1912 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Taft Letters - Varying Dates, 1903-1912 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Summary of ILR 100, 1975-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Labor in Colonial America (Box 7, Folder 2)
- The Working Class and the American Revolution, 1946-1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Beginnings of the Labor Movement, 1913-1946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Jacksonian Democracy and the Working Class, 1947-1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Political Movements, 1827-1833, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Trade Union Movement, 1833-1837, 1892-1955 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Utopian Schemes and Coops, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Factory Workers, 1950-1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Industrial Revolution (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Unions in the Ante-Bellum Decade and 1860s to 1873, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Northern Labor and Slavery, 1943-1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Includes a news clipping
- National Labor Union, 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Knights of Labor, 1950-1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Nature and Philosophy of the American Federation of Labor, 1956-1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Rise of the National Union, 1913-1957 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Stabilization and Growth, 1886-1904 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Violence and Industrialization, 1973-1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Molly Maguires, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Railroad Strikes of 1877, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Haymarket Tragedy (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Homestead Strike, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Pullman Boycott and Strike, 1957-1967 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Steunenberg Murder (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), 1920-1977 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- IWW to World War I, 1920-1956 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Why the Labor Movement is not Revolutionary, 1957-1975 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Worker and Working Conditions, 1965-1977 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Immigration, 1919-1974 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Progressive Era, Labor Politics, and the Socialist Party, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Decline of the AFL, 1969-1977 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Labor on the Defensive (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Labor During World War I, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Union-Management Cooperation and Organization, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Brookwood Labor College (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Attacks on Brookwood and Formation of CPLA (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Scientific Management and the Unions, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Rise of the CIO, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Toward Labor's Civil War (Box 7, Folder 39)
- CIO, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Non-Organizational Aspects of the CIO Movement, 1955-1957 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Industrial vs. Craft Unionism (Box 7, Folder 42)
- AFL's Non-Labor Alignments, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Labor During the Great Depression, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Labor and the New Deal, 1933-1935 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- AFL Organizing, 1933-1935 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Labor During World War II, 1968-1982 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Communism and the Labor Movement, 1957-1978 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- AFL-CIO Merger, 1955-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- McClellan Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Current Problems and Prospects I, 1957-1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Current Problems and Prospects II, 1972-1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Current Problems and Prospects III, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Current Membership, 1972-1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Air Line Pilots Association (ALPA) - Outlines, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- ALPA, 1966-1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- ALPA Clippings 1, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- ALPA Clippings 2, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- ALPA Clippings 3, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- ALPA Clippings 4, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- ALPA Clippings 5Includes news clippings, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- United Farm Workers (UFW) - Lecture Outline, 1964-1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- UFW Clippings 1, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- UFW Clippings 2, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- UFW Clippings 3, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- UFW Clippings 4, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- UFW Clippings 5, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- UFW Clippings 6, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- UFW - Farm Labor Force, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- UFW - Articles, 1962-1975 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  1979-
- UFW - Articles continued, 1974-1977 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- UFW - Legislation, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- UFW - Releases, etc., 1964-1976 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  Includes news clippings; includes a UFW grape boycott sticker
- Farm Labor, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  Includes some Spanish language material; contents are all copies of "El Malcriado," the newspaper of the UFW
- United Mine Workers (UMW) - Outlines, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- UMW Clippings 1, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- UMW Clippings 2, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- UMW Clippings 3, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- UMW Clippings 4, 1973-1979 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- UMW Clippings 5, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- UMW Clipping 6, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- UMW Articles, 1959-1974 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- United Mine Workers (UMW) Articles, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT) - Outlines, 1975-1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- IBT Clippings 1, 1967-1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- IBT Clippings 2, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- IBT Clippings 3, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- IBT Clippings 4, 1979-1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Hoffa - Review of Sheridan, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Clipping from the New York Times Book Review
- IBT - Mollenhoff (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Excerpt from Mollenhoff's book Tentacles of Power
- Hoffa's Commutation in 1971, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- IBT - PROD (Professional Drivers Council), 1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- IBT - Articles, 1963-1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Public Employees, 1967-1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 1957-1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Rail Unions, 1968-1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Teachers, 1966-1977 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Teachers Collective Bargaining, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- UAW (United Automobile Workers), 1958-1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Policemen, 1969-1980 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- NMU (National Maritime Union), 1975 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Rubber Workers, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Meat Cutters, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- CWA (Communication Workers of America), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- TWU (Transport Workers Union), 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Pulp, Sulfite and Paper Mill Workers, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Carpenters, 1969-1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- ILA (International Longshoremen's Association), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- USW (United Steel Workers), 1960-1983 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- ANA (American Nurses' Association), 1967 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Labor Reform Act of 1977 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Labor Reform Act of 1977 articles, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Labor and the Law Outlines, 1951-1981 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Labor and the Law, 1957-1977 (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Labor Reform Act of 1977 - President Carter's Message to Congress (Box 9, Folder 34)
- NLRB (National Labor Relations Board), 1975-1979 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Labor and the Law - Criminal Conspiracy, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Taft-Hartley and Full Employment Acts, 1952-1972 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Landrun Griffin Act, 1959-1971 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Right-to-Work Laws, 1954-1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- National Emergency Strikes - Cullen, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- NLRB Decisions, 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)